UTTAMKUMAR TARASARIYA

Etobicoke, ON M9W 7G6 437 9717179 uttamtarsariya@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/uttam kumar-tarasariya-5759421b7/

ABOUT ME

A motivated Artificial Intelligence enthusiast with Certified AWS Machine Leaning Specialist. Have been passionate about how AI can add value to almost any situation and environment. Therefore, whenever It can be possible, allocate time to continue training in AI and ML, as well as in product ideation, discovery, and definition. Diligent worker, good planner and swift learner.

Core Skills

Data Scraping
Data Analysis
Data Engineering
Cloud resources configuration (AWS, Google)
Machine Learning
Deep Learning

Reinforcement learning Time series, Forcasting, Computer Vision, Recommendation system, Natural Language Processing, AI-ML on AWS Sagemaker,

HIGHLIGHTS

- Good knowledge of Machine Learning and Deep Learning including libraries pandas, scikit-learn, nltk, pytorch, tensorflow and more.
- Developed a computer vision project using Machine Learning.
- Worked with images and videos real-time analysis using OpenCv
- Trained, tuned and deployed Machine Learning models including xGBoost, classification/regression models for real time inference on AWS Cloud.
- Configured cloud computing resources such as CPUs, GPUs, data pipelines, storages to manage ML DL models.

EDUCATION

Loyalist College in Toronto, North York, Canada

Artificial Intelligence and Data Science Ontario College Graduate Certificate in Artificial Intelligence and Data Science May '21 - Present GPA: 3.9

Government Engineering College, Rajkot, India

Bachelor of Engineering - Computer Engineering Gujarat Technological University - Ahmedabad May '15 - Apr '19 GPA : 3.0

WORK EXPERIENCE

Artificial Intelligence Engineer (AI-AWS Developer) - PlanetX IT Services Pvt. Ltd. - Surat, India

Nov '20 - Dec'21

- AWS cloud compute resource configurations
- Data Engineering tasks including data gathering-cleaning-analyzing and preparing to input
- Working with AWS Sagemaker to build, train, tune and deploy Machine Learning Models, Deep Learning Networks, Computer vision applications deployments
- Resource, data and model security

Mobile Engineer - PlanetX IT Services Pvt. Ltd. - Surat, India

May 2018 - August 2020

- Development of Android mobile applications using Java and Kotlin
- Communicate with clients to ensure workflow matches requirements properly
- Update requirements and deliverables to fullfill changed requirements
- Publish applications on Google playstore and app store
- · Train juniors to ensure their better training

OMNI associate - Walmart Store - Toronto, Canada

June 2021 - Oct 2021 (Part time)

- · Work with the team
- · Accomplishes organisation mission by completing related results as needed.
- Orders management using Walmart GHS inventory management system
- Stock and zone the items accordingly and as required
- Learned operation of handling online orders to ensure a smooth process.

Ship-Dock associate - Amazon Warehouse - Toronto, Canada

Nov 2021 - Present (Part time)

- Work with the team and follow safety rules and procedures.
- Orders management task, pick, sort using Amazon order management system
- · Scan and update parcel's locations in the system to inform customers accordingly
- · Learned to work and co-operate with bigger staff with about a thousand of employees

PROJECTS

Realtime Video Masking - Computer Vision and Deep Learning Application

· Researched and documented procedure and libraries

Present

- Used AWS Rekognition for finding sensitive information such as faces, number plates from the video content captured by sensors installed in the car and using OpenCV packages for blurring the information.
- Developed a platform to upload video, apply masks on some objects and store it
- Cooperated and synchronized with Testing operated by QA team

Image Recognition - Computer Vision Application

 Developed a platform for restaurant menu Text Extraction from Daily Menus Image Jan '22

- Managed Flow: Get Image of menu from restaurant manager uisng AWS
 API Gateway, manage it using AWS Lambda, extract the text using
 Amazon Textract Deep Learning Algorithm and respond to them with
 detailed information like item with price, special offers, discounts etc.
- Deployed platform on the AWS cloud for real time usage.

Social Platform for matching like profiles - Deep Learning Application

• Aim is to connect people with equal likes

Mar' 22

- Set up AWS Resources to get all registered users profiles for preparing dataset.
- Configured and managed pipelines to input data to Machine Learning model
- Designed, trained, tunedd, and deployed several machine Learning classification models to get higher accuracy
- Configured AWS API Gateway, AWS Lambda, DynamoDB and other required resources
- Cooperated and synchronized with Testing operated by QA team

Spam Message Classification - Machine Learning Application

• Collected data of the messages to train model

Dec '21

- Cleaned and balanced dataset to increase the accuracy and better training of model
- Builded, trained, tuned and deployed xGBoost Machine Learning classification model for classifying emails
- Managed AWS Resources including AWS Lambda, AWS Sagemaker, Storage, AWS API Gateways.
- Deployed model and generated endpoint for realtime testing

Recommendation System - Deep Learning Application

- Aim is to build recommendations
- Initially used Amazon data and review to get start
- Build, trainined, tuned and deployed model on AWS Cloud
- Parallelly gathering original data from shopping website
- Configured and managed all services including pipeline, AWS Glue for performing ETL tasks and data storage.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages

R - Python Java Script

Frontend: Java, Kotlin, ReactJs, React Native

backend: NodeJs

Databases

SOL

DynamoDB, MongoDB Google Firebase Databases on AWS

Tools and Technologies

AWS Sagemaker AWS (Glue ETL, Kinesis, S3, AWS Lambda, API Gateway, AWS Comprehend, AWS Translate, AWS Transcribe, Polly and other related to AI) Python (keras, sklearn, pycharm, Opencv, YOLO) IDEs (jupyter, pycharm)

Soft skills

Proactive
Research and development, reading and
preparing procedure document
Problem solving

Platform (GCP, AWS)
Visualization (PowerBI, Tablue,
seaborn, matplotlib)
Microsoft Excel
Version Control (Github, BitBucket)
OS (Linux, Windows)

Working and contributing team Communication

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Machine Learning Specialty - Expert Level

By AWS (Amazon Web Services)

Machine Learning A-Z $^{\rm TM}$: Hands-On Python & R In Data Science - Learning Certifications

Deep Learning A-Z™: Hands-On Artificial Neural Networks

Artificial Intelligence A-Z™: Learn How To Build An Al

By Udemy online

Mar '22

May '21 - Nov '22

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Coordinator of Programming events during the academic session.
- participated in C-Quiz in GEC IT events Rajkot
- Represented Government Engineering College, Rajkot in Writing Competition.

Feb'22